Welcome back, in this video we're gonna talk about the key ideas behind techniques
欢迎回来，在这段视频中，我们将谈论技术背后的关键思想
for recognizing handles. There is good news and bad news when it comes to
用于识别句柄。当涉及到的时候，有好消息和坏消息
recognizing handles. The bad news is that there is no known efficient algorithm that
识别句柄。坏消息是，目前还没有已知的高效算法
recognizes handles in general. So for an arbitrary grammar, we don't have a fast
通常可以识别句柄。所以对于任意的语法，我们没有快速
way to find the handles when we're parsing. The good news is that there are
我们在解析时找到句柄的方法。好消息是，有
heuristics for guessing handles, and for some context free grammars, for some
猜测句柄的启发式方法，以及一些上下文无关语法的启发式方法
fairly large classes of context free grammars, these heuristics always identify
相当大的上下文无关文法类，这些启发式方法总是识别
the handles correctly. We can illustrate the situation with a Venn diagram. If we
手柄正确。我们可以用维恩图来说明情况。如果我们
start with a set of all context free grammars, then the unambiguous context
从一组所有上下文无关文法开始，然后是明确的上下文
free grammars are a sub-set of those, and then an even smaller set are called the
自由文法是这些文法的一个子集，然后还有一个更小的文法集被称为
LR(k) grammars. And here, just to remind you, 'l' stands for left to right scan,
LR(K)文法。这里，提醒一下，‘l’代表从左向右扫描，
'r' stands for rightmost variation, and 'k' stands for the number of tokens of
‘r’代表最右边的变体，‘k’代表的令牌数
look ahead. Now the LRK grammars are one of the most general deterministic families
往前看。目前，LRK文法是最普遍的确定性文法之一
of deterministic grammars that we know of. But those aren't the ones that are
我们所知道的决定论语法。但那些不是
actually used in practice. Most of the bottom up tools that are practical, use
实际上是在实践中使用的。大多数实用的自下而上工具都使用
what are called the LALRK grammars, which are a subset of the LRK grammars. And then
这就是所谓的LALRK文法，它是LRK文法的子集。然后
what we're gonna talk mostly about is a simplification of those called the simple
我们将主要讨论的是那些被称为简单的
LR grammars, or the SLRK context free grammars. And these containment
LR文法，或SLRK上下文无关文法。而这些遏制措施
relationships or [inaudible] that is, there are grammars that are [inaudible]. R
关系或[听不见]也就是说，有一些语法是[听不见的]。R
k but not s l r k, for every k, and similarly there are grammars that are l r
而不是s，l，r，k，对于每个k，类似地，有一些语法是l，r
k for every k that are not l a l r k. As we've already said, it's not obvious how
对于不是l，a，l，r，k的每一个k，正如我们已经说过的，并不是很明显
to detect handles. So, what does the parser know? Well, it sees the stack. At
要检测句柄，请执行以下操作。那么，解析器知道什么呢？嗯，它看到的是堆栈。在…
each step it knows the stack that it has already, constructed. And so let's see how
它的每一步都知道它已经构建的堆栈。所以让我们看看如何
much progress we can make just thinking about, what information we can get from
光是想一想，我们就可以取得很多进步，我们可以从哪些信息中获得
the stack. So here's a definition. We're going to say that alpha is a viable
堆栈。所以这里有一个定义。我们要说阿尔法是一个可行的
prefix. If there is some omega, such that alpha bar omega is a configuration, a
前缀。如果存在一些ω，使得阿尔法条ω是一种配置，则
valid configuration of a shift reduce parse. Now keep in mind that the alpha
Shift Reduce分析的有效配置。现在请记住，阿尔法
here. This is the stack. And the omega here is the rest of the input. And what
这里。这是堆栈。这里的欧米茄是输入的睡觉。还有什么
does that means? That means the parser knows this part. The parser knows alpha,
那是不是意味着？这意味着解析器知道这一部分。解析器知道阿尔法，
it doesn't know much of omega. It can do some look-ahead, it can look at a small
它对欧米茄了解不多。它可以做一些前瞻，它可以看小的
prefix of omega, usually just one token, but it certainly doesn't know the whole
omega的前缀，通常只有一个标记，但它肯定不知道整个
thing. So what does a viable prefix mean? Well, a viable prefix is a string that
一件事。那么，一个可行的前缀是什么意思呢？一个可行的前缀是一个字符串，该字符串
does not extend past the right end of the handle. And the reason we call it a viable
不会超出手柄的右端。我们之所以称它为一种可行的
prefix is because it is a prefix of the handle. So as long as the parser has
前缀是因为它是句柄的前缀。所以只要解析器有
viable prefixes on the stack, no parsing error has been detected. And really the
堆栈上的可行前缀，未检测到分析错误。而且真的是
definition is just giving a name to something, it's not anything very deep,
定义就是给某物起个名字，它不是很深奥的东西，
the fact that alpha bar omega is, is viable, that's just saying we haven't
阿尔法条欧米伽是，是可行的，这只是说我们还没有
encountered an error. That this is some state of a shift reduce parse. It hasn't
遇到错误。这是某种移位归约解析状态。它还没有
said yet how we're going to identity it or anything like that; it's just saying that
还说我们将如何识别它或诸如此类的东西；它只是说
these are the valid states of shift reduced parse. Now the definition is
这些是移位简化解析的有效状态。现在的定义是
useful in one way if it bring us to the last important fact, important fact number
如果它把我们带到最后一个重要的事实，重要的事实数字，在某种程度上是有用的
three about bottom up parsing. In this effort, any grammar, the set of viable
三是关于自下而上的解析。在这种努力下，任何语法、集合都是可行的
prefixes is a regular language, and this is really an amazing fact, and one that's
前缀是一种常规语言，这确实是一个令人惊叹的事实，也是
going to take us a little while to demonstrate, but this is the key to bottom
我们要花点时间来演示，但这是进入谷底的关键
up parsing. At least all the bottom up parsing tools are based on this fact, that
向上解析。至少所有自下而上的解析工具都是基于这一事实的，即
the set of viable prefix can be recognized by a finite automaton. So, we're going to
可行前缀集合可以由有限自动机识别。所以，我们要去
show how to compute this automaton that accepts the viable prefixes, but first
演示如何计算接受可行前缀的自动机，但首先
we're going to need a number of additional definitions. The first definition we need
我们需要一些额外的定义。我们需要的第一个定义是
is the idea of an item. Now an item is a production that just has a dot somewhere
是一件物品的想法。现在，一件物品就是在某处有一个圆点的作品
on the right hand side. So here's an example. Let's take the production, T goes
在右手边。这里有一个例子。让我们拿着这部作品，T走吧
to open paren, E closed paren. What we're going to do is we're just gonna put the
要打开Paren，E关闭Paren。我们要做的就是把
dot in eve ry possible position on the right hand side. So we'll have one item
在右手边每一个可能的位置上都有点。所以我们要一件
where the dot is all the way at the left end. We'll have one where the dot is all
这里的圆点一直在左端。我们会有一个圆点都是的
the way at the right end. And then we'll have, items where the dot is between every
路在右边的尽头。然后我们会有一些项目，这些项目的圆点在
pair of consecutive symbols. So in this case, there are four items for the
一对连续的符号。因此，在本例中，有四项用于
production. One special case is, what do we do with epsilon productions? Well, for
制作。一个特例是，我们如何处理epsilon产品？嗯，因为
an epsilon production, there is no, there are no symbols on the right hand side.
一个epsilon制作，没有，在右手边没有符号。
We'll just say there is one item, X goes to dot. And these items, you'll see them
我们只说有一项，X去圆点。而这些物品，你会看到它们
referred to, if you, if you look in help, pages and in the literature, as, the LR
如果您在帮助、页面和文献中查找，则称为LR
zero items. Now we're ready to discuss how we recognize viable prefixes. And the
零个项目。现在我们准备讨论如何识别可行的前缀。以及
problem is that the stack has only bits and pieces of the right hand side of
问题是堆栈只有右侧的零星部分
productions. In general most of the time, we don't have a complete right hand side
制作。一般来说，在大多数情况下，我们没有一个完整的右手边
on top of the stack. Most of the time, we only have a part of the right hand side.
在堆栈的顶部。大多数时候，我们只有右手边的一部分。
And. It turns out that what is on the stack is actually not just random it's,
和。事实证明，堆栈上的内容实际上不仅仅是随机的，
it's it actually has a very special structure. In, in these bits and pieces
它实际上有一个非常特殊的结构。在，在这些零星的东西里
are always prefixes of right hand sides of productions. That is in any successful
始终是积的右手边的前缀。那就是在任何成功的
parse what is on the stack always has to be a prefix of the right hand side of some
分析堆栈上的内容始终必须是某些
production or productions. Let's take a look at an example. Let's consider the
制作或制作。让我们来看一个例子。让我们考虑一下
input open paren, [inaudible] closed paren. And here's one of our favorite
输入打开Paren、[听不见]关闭Paren。这是我们最喜欢的
grammars. Now, this configurations, where I have open paren E, [inaudible], on the
语法。现在，这个配置，其中我打开了Paren E，[听不见]，在
stack. Remember that this is our stack. And we have the close [inaudible] in the
堆栈。请记住，这是我们的堆栈。我们有闭合[听不见]在
input. This is actually a state or a valid state of a shift [inaudible]. And you can
输入。这实际上是转换的一种状态或有效状态[听不见]。而且你可以
see here that, open paren E is a prefix of the production. T goes to open paren E,
看这里，开放的Paren E是作品的前缀。T去打开Paren E，
close paren. And after we shift the remaining close paren onto the stack, then
合上帕伦。在我们将剩余的Close Paren移到堆栈上之后，然后
we'll have the complete right hand side, and it will be ready to reduce. So this is
我们会有完整的右手边，它会准备好减少。那么这就是
where the items come in. The item, T goes to open paren E. Dot, closed paren. This
这些物品是从哪里进来的。项目T去打开Paren E.Dot，关闭Paren。这
describes this state of affairs. I t says that so far, we have seen open paren E of
描述了这种情况。它说到目前为止，我们已经看到了公开赛的
this production. And we're hoping in the future to see the closed paren. So another
这部作品。我们希望将来能看到关门的帕伦。所以又是另一个
way of thinking about it is that this item records the fact that we're working on
我们可以这样想，这个项目记录了我们正在研究的
this production. And then so far we've seen this much. Everything to the left of
这部作品。到目前为止，我们已经看到了这么多。左边的所有东西
the dot is what we've already seen and is what is on the stack and. What is to the
点是我们已经看到的，也是堆栈上的。这对我们来说有什么意义呢？
right of the dot is what we're waiting to see before we could possibly reduce. And
点的右边是我们在可能减少之前等待看到的。和
we may or may not see that, remember, the parser doesn't know the input. In this
我们可能看到也可能没有看到，记住，解析器不知道输入。在这里面
case of course, it's the very next, next symbol and so it can see in the
当然，它就是下一个，下一个符号，所以它可以在
look-ahead, but you know at this point in time the parser doesn't know for sure
向前看，但是您知道，在这个时间点上，解析器还不能确定
what's coming up and, you know, and, and, if this dot were further to the left there
接下来是什么，你知道的，如果这个点再往左一点
might be many, many more symbols that we had to go, before we could perform the
可能会有更多的符号，在我们可以表演之前，我们必须要去掉更多的符号
reduction. So anyway, what's to the left of that records what we've already seen.
减少。不管怎样，左边的内容记录了我们已经看到的东西。
And what is to the right of the dot, says that what we are waiting to see on the
这个点右边的是，我们在等着看的东西，就是我们正在等着看的东西，也就是我们正在等着看的东西。
stack, before we can perform a reduction. And now we could talk about the structure
堆栈，然后我们才能执行缩减。现在我们可以谈谈它的结构
of the stack. So you see it's not just arbitrary collections of symbols. In fact,
堆栈中的。所以你可以看到，这不仅仅是任意的符号集合。事实上,
it has this very particular structure. So the stack is actually a stack of prefixes
它有一个非常特殊的结构。因此堆栈实际上是一堆前缀
of right hand sides. So the stack always has this organization where there's a
右手边的。所以堆栈总是有这样的组织，其中有一个
bunch of prefixes, stacked up, literally stacked up on the stack. And what's going
一堆前缀，堆叠在一起，字面意思是堆叠在一起。那到底是怎么回事呢？
to happen is that the ice prefix, if you were to pick a prefix out of this stack of
如果你从这个堆栈中选择一个前缀，就会发生冰块前缀
prefixes, While that must be the prefix of some production. Okay. The right hand side
前缀，而这必须是某些产品的前缀。好吧。右手边
of sum production And what that means is that, that prefix, that [inaudible] prefix
它的意思是，前缀，那个[听不见的]前缀
on the stack, will eventually reduce to the left hand side of that production. So
在堆栈上，最终会减少到生产的左手边。所以
it will eventually reduce to, XI in this case. And then that XI has to be Part of
在这种情况下，它最终将简化为XI。那么XI就必须是
the missing suffix, of the prefix that is below it on the stack. So if I look at the
堆栈中位于其下方的前缀的缺少后缀。所以如果我看一下
previous prefix the one that's right below, prefix [inaudible] on the stack
上一个前缀正下方的那个，在堆栈上加[听不见]的前缀
Then when I perform this reducti on that XI needs to extend that prefix to be
然后，当我对该XI执行此缩减时，需要将该前缀扩展为
closer to a complete right hand side of that particular reduction. Okay so in
更接近于那个特定减影的完全右侧。好的，那么进来吧
particular there's going to be some production. That is going to; already have
特别是会有一些生产。将要发生的；已经发生的
a portion of its right hand side on the stack. So prefix of I minus one. And X I
它的右手边的一部分在堆叠上。所以前缀i减1。和X i
is going to extend that prefix, and then there's gonna be some more stuff possibly
会扩展这个前缀，然后可能会有更多的东西
that we're waiting to see, even after the X I is put there. And recursively, all the
我们拭目以待，即使在X i被放在那里之后也是如此。递归地，所有的
prefixes above prefix K eventually have to reduce to the missing part of the right
前缀K以上的前缀最终必须减少到右侧缺失的部分
hand side of prefix K, the alpha K that goes on the right hand side. [inaudible]
前缀K的手边，右手边的字母K。[听不见]
This image, you have a stack of prefixes we're always working on the top-most
这张图片，你有一堆我们一直在处理的前缀，最上面
prefix on the stack, so you will be always working here on the right and shifting and
堆栈上的前缀，因此您将始终在这里向右操作，并移动和
reducing, but every time we perform a reduction. That has to extend the prefix
减少，但每次我们执行减少。它必须扩展前缀
immediately below it on the stack. And when these, when a bunch of prefixes have
就在堆栈上它的正下方。当这些，当一堆前缀有
been removed from the stack through reductions, then we, when we get to work
通过减量从堆栈中移除，然后我们，当我们开始工作的时候
on the prefixes that are lower in the stack. So let's illustrate this idea with
在堆栈中位置较低的前缀上。那么让我们用以下几个例子来说明这个想法
an example. So here is another input string, and we're gonna use the same
举个例子。这是另一个输入字符串，我们将使用相同的
grammar. You can, you can rewind if you want to see the grammar again. But let's
语法。你可以，如果你想再看一遍语法，你可以倒回去。但是让我们
consider this state where we have open paren, [inaudible] star on the stack. And
考虑这样的状态，我们在堆栈上有打开的Paren，[听不见]星。和
we have int, close paren remaining in the input, 'kay? And so what items would
我们有INT，CLOSE Paren保留在输入中，‘好吗？那么什么项目会
record, what is the, what is the stack structure here and how do the items record
记录，什么是，这里的堆栈结构是什么，项目是如何记录的
it? Well let's start here at the bottom, let's actually work from the bottom up. So
它?好的，让我们从底部开始，让我们真正地从下往上做。所以
we have in start the top of our stack, so we this is the right hand side that we're
我们从堆栈的顶部开始，所以我们这是我们的右手边
currently working on, and that would be a prefix to this production T goes to int
目前正在开发中，这将是这个产品的前缀T Go to int
star T. Okay? So what this says is that we're looking you know, we, we've seen in
星T好吗？所以这说明我们正在寻找，你知道，我们，我们已经在
stars so far, and we're waiting to see [inaudible]. I'm not showing the items,
到目前为止星星很多，我们在等着看[听不见]。我不会展示物品的，
but I'm just showing the productions that this is eventually going to use. Now, the
但我只是展示最终会用到的作品。现在，
one that's below it here, the, the prefix that's below it o n the stack is right
它下面的这个，它下面的那个堆栈的前缀是对的
here in between the open paren and the int. This one's an interesting case. It's
在开放的Paren和INT之间。这是个有趣的案子。它是
actually epsilon. So there's nothing there now on the stack. But eventually once the
实际上是埃西隆。所以现在堆栈上什么都没有了。但最终一旦
int star has reduced to T. Okay? Then that T is going to reduce to E. And currently,
INT STAR已降为T，明白吗？那么T就会减少到E，而目前，
of course, there's not a T there at all. So we've only seen epsilon. We've seen
当然，那里根本没有T。所以我们只看到了埃西隆。我们已经看到
none of the prefix of this production on the stack. And then for the last
堆栈上没有此产品的前缀。然后最后一次
production, the one deepest in the stack, we're currently, we've currently seen an
生产，堆栈中最深的一个，我们目前，我们目前已经看到
open paren. And, we're w-, and we think we're working on this production. T goes
打开帕伦。而且，我们.，我们认为我们正在制作这部作品。T走了
to open paren, E closed paren, alright? So when this E is produced, that will extend
打开帕伦，E关闭帕伦，好吗？所以当这个E产生时，它会延伸
this right hand side. And now we can record all of this with the stack of
这是右手边。现在我们可以用堆栈记录所有这些
items, T goes to open paren dot E, E goes to dot T, and T goes to N star dot T.
项目，T用来打开Paren点E，E用来打开T点，T用来打开N星点T。
Okay, and we just record what we said on the previous slide, that so far, we see
好的，我们只录制上一张幻灯片上说的内容，到目前为止，我们看到
the open paren of this production. We've seen nothing out of the right hand side of
这部作品中的开诚布公的帕伦。我们没有看到右手边有任何东西
this production, and we've seen N star so far of this production. And just notice
这部作品，到目前为止我们已经看到了这部作品的N星。你只要注意到
how the left hand side of each of these productions is going to eventually become
这些作品的左手边最终会变成什么样子
part of the right hand side of the. Of the right, part of the right hand side of the
右手边的一部分。右手边的一部分，右手边的一部分
production we are working on just below it in the stack. So when we've reduced this
我们正在进行的生产工作就在堆栈中它的正下方。所以当我们减少了这个
instar T to T that will extend this production, when it reaches E that will
将T增加到T，这将扩展此生产，当达到E时，将
extend this production To summarize this video, we can say a little more precisely
延伸这部作品来总结这段视频，我们可以说得更准确一点
how we go about recognizing viable prefixes. The crux of the problem is going
我们如何识别可行的前缀。问题的症结在于
to be to recognize a sequence of partial right had sides of production. Where each
承认部分权利序列是有生产方面的。其中每个
of those partial right hand sides can eventually reduce to part of the missing
这些部分右手边的部分最终可能会减少到丢失的部分
suffix of its predecessor Next time, in the next video we're going to actually
它的前身的后缀，在下一个视频中，我们将实际
give the algorithm for implementing this idea.
给出了实现这一思想的算法。